140 48TH ST SE

PARIS, TX 75462 USA

TEL: (+1) 469-893-0681

https://github.com/maxArturo
maxarturo@gmail.com
https://maxalcala.com

SUMMARY

Software engineer with buisness and customer-facing experience in both Fortune 50 companies and startups. My experience has ranged from individual contributor (including a Principal role), to managing large teams onshore and offshore. My current interests cover language parsers/compilers, literate programming, and the art of fostering a healthy company culture.

SKILLS

NOTE: The following list of technologies and languages is not exhaustive nor comprehensive for practicality; please reach out if a particular language or framework matters to you.

- PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: TS/ES7/ESNext/JS, Kotlin, Ruby, Golang, Common Lisp, Rust, Dart, VBA/VBS, sh/bash/zsh, LATEX, most markup and hypertext languages.
- FRAMEWORKS AND STORAGE: GraphQL, message queues, Rails, NextJS/most JS frameworks, Reactive Extensions (particularly Rx.js). Varied functional programming experience (Haskell, Elm, functional TS libraries). RDBMS/NoSQL/K-V persisted storage, as well general caching components and libraries.
- DEVOPS/CI: Jenkins/Teamcity/GH actions, deployments via Docker and containerization, Kubernetes/istio. AWS/GCP/Azure management, cost tuning and other general tasks (IAM, TF/deployment troubleshooting), etc. Instrumentation and measurement, bash scripting and basic Linux server management. Previous Terraform/Chef exposure. Automated testing/e2e via Playwright/Cypress/Puppeteer.
- FRONTEND/MOBILE: HTML5, CSS preprocessors, Javascript/precompilers (Babel/TypeScript). Mobile primarily via Flutter. Client-side data visualization and processing (d3, crossfilter, SVGs), React.js, Redux, Angular 6/7/8. No-JS frameworks (HTMX, tachyons.css)
- MANAGEMENT/PE/TECH LEAD: Work at any level of abstraction within management (process requirements, deliverables, proof-of-concept). Excellent analytical, communication and problem-solving skills. Seasoned interviewer and hiring manager. Previous experience working directly with Fortune 50 VPs as well as directly with end-users. Experienced leading offshore, as well as onshore teams.

NATURAL LANGUAGES: Native Spanish, Intermediate Japanese.

CERTIFICATIONS: AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

EXPERIENCE

PriceWaterhouseCoopers, LLC (PwC)

PwC Labs - Principal Engineer

CHICAGO, IL 2021-2023

- Led design and implementation of blockchain auditing solutions for PwC Labs
- Provided technical leadership, executed on mission-critical components and prioritized projects with senior leadership
- Spearheaded blockchain research, PoC and upskilling via hands-on seminars
- Support and mentor offshore developers. Encouraged best practices, industry-standard patterns, and performed architectural analysis
- Stack: ES6/Typescript, Angular 5, Node.js, GCP Suite, Docker, Kubernetes, Firebase, Jenkins, Postgres

Clearcover.com

CHICAGO, IL

Lead Software Engineer

2019 - 2021

- Lead team responsible for successfully delivering the company's core Policy Management API
- Build templating system for generating insurance forms via AWS/Puppeteer/Node apis
- Pair, upskill, and unblock team members to maximize their productivity and promote a healthy dev team culture
- Stack: Functional Typescript(v3.x), Rails, Kotlin, AWS/K8s, Postgres

PriceWaterhouseCoopers, LLC (PwC)

CHICAGO, IL

New Ventures Practice - Tech Lead

2017 - 2019 SaaS offerings

- Provide technical leadership for multiple greenfield SaaS offerings across all aspects of the SDLC
- Responsible for all aspects of technical execution for product vision: Architecture, hands-on development, infrastructure, code quality/best practices, hiring, runbooks, etc.
- Lead offshore developers with a supportive environment, mentoring and industry-standard patterns
- Promote successful development team behaviors (developer-led estimations, people over process) in the firm
- Stack: ES6/Typescript, Angular 5, Node.js, GCP Suite, Docker, Kubernetes, Firebase, Jenkins, Postgres

ReviewTrackers

CHICAGO, IL

Senior Software Developer

2017

- Deliver features across the entire stack to unlock company growth
- Support team efficiency by automating tasks and workflows
- Pair-program and mentor junior developers
- Measure performance and find optimization solutions
- Stack: React, Golang. Ruby, Solr, Heroku/AWS, React, Node.js, Postgres

Shoppertrak CHICAGO, IL Senior Software Developer/Team Lead 2015 - 2016

- Own and maintain the Node API for the company's main reporting app

- Manage the tasks for my team and prioritize with PMs and Tech Architect
- Promote best practices in my team, pair-program and mentor teammates
- Configure CI tools, provision, deploy and document server infrastructure requirements
- Stack: Angular, Node.js, AWS, Redshift/PG, TeamCity

Tukaiz, LLC

CHICAGO, IL

Software Developer

May - Oct 2015

- Support Rails 2.3.8, 3, & 4 applications
- Refactored large legacy VB codebase into Ruby
- Re-implemented file management scheduler with Rails/Sidekiq

Gearbox Software

DALLAS, TX

Software Developer - Contractor

May - Dec 2015

- Implement Battleborn Game launch and Beta registration sites with Ruby/Rails
- Collaborate on UX flows and internal API flow

EDUCATION

_	M.S. Supply Chain Management	GPA:	3.72
٠	M.S. Supply Chain Management University of Texas at Dallas	Dec	2012
•	B.S. Operations Management, Minor in Computer Science		3.94
	University of Texas at Dallas: Summa Cum Laude, Dean's	<i>List</i> Dec	2011
	Donnguk University-Seoul, South Korea	MARCH-JUN	2010
	MIS Exchange Program	GPA:	3.95

PROJECTS AND OSS

- **Vamonos MGP:** A flutter ios/Android app to assist the general public in the Puerreydon municipality of Argentina with public transportation arrival times. App Store link
- maxarturo.github.io: A Common Lisp static site generator that allows for arbitrary s-expression execution within the context of Markdown files. hosted under maxalcala.com
- cl-peg-yapp: Product Expression Grammar (PEG) parser, code generator and meta-parser built from first principles in SBCL. Parses its own grammar and allows for PEG bottom-up testing and literate coding. link
- zod: Contributed Collaborated on the GH project. A versatile TS run-time type
 validator. gh link and commits
- jibun (WIP): An efficient, linear-time Hitori puzzle generator, with a React frontend. It improves upon the state-of-the-art with a novel graph algorithm to generate covered squares, and Knuth's DLX exact-cover algorithm to generate numbers.